[upbeat music]
[欢快的音乐]
♪ ♪
- [humming]
- [嗡嗡声]
One glorious week
辉煌的一周
without being annoyed
by those two--
不生气
由那两个人——
- Hey!
- 嘿！
- [wailing]
- [哀号]
Idiots!
白痴！
both: Hi, Squidward!
两人：嗨，章鱼哥！
- Whoo-hoo!
Doink.
- 呼呼！
多因克。
Hold on, Squidward.
坚持住，章鱼哥。
[both straining]
[双方都紧张]
You should be more careful.
你应该更加小心。
- Tsk-tsk-tsk.
- 啧啧啧。
- Would you two go away
and stop ruining my vacation?
- 你们两个可以走开吗
别再毁了我的假期吗？
- Vacation?
- 假期？
Gee, I didn't think
Mr. Krabs gave us any vacation.
哎呀我没想到
蟹老板给了我们任何假期。
- I found someone
to cover for me.
- 我找到了一个人
为我掩护。
- One krabby patty
coming up, sir.
- 一份蟹肉饼
即将到来，先生。
[groaning]
[呻吟]
[sizzling]
Huh? [sniffs]
[嘶嘶声]
啊？ [嗅嗅]
- Where are you going on
your vacation, Squidward?
- 你要去哪里
你的假期吗，章鱼哥？
- If you must know,
I'm going to Porpoise Peak
- 如果你一定要知道的话
我要去海豚峰
to bask in the melodious sounds
of the Warbling Water Lily.
沐浴在悠扬的声音中
鸣叫的睡莲。
[both exclaiming]
[两人惊呼]
Which only blooms once
every 500 years.
只开一次花的
每 500 年一次。
And I'm going alone.
而我一个人去。
- I know!
- 我知道！
Patrick and I will come along
帕特里克和我会一起去
and we can all
be alone together.
我们都可以
单独在一起。
- Oh, no!
- 哦，不！
You're not
messing up my vacation.
你不是
搞乱了我的假期。
Now beat it!
现在打败它！
If I don't get moving,
I'm going to miss it.
如果我不行动起来
我会想念它的。
- Oh, we'll help you pack.
- 哦，我们会帮你打包。
- No way.
You idiots will just break--
- 决不。
你们这些白痴只会崩溃——
Everything. Oh.
一切。哦。
- Hold it.
- 握住它。
Forgot to pack this.
忘记打包这个了。
- What, no!
Don't! Stop!
- 什么，不！
不！停止！
- [chuckles]
- [轻笑]
- [screams]
- [尖叫]
- Oh, oh, oh!
[horns honking]
- 哦，哦，哦！
[喇叭鸣响]
all: Oh!
全体：哦！
- Oh, no!
- 哦，不！
[together]
Whew!
[一起]
哇！
[metal clanks]
[金属叮当声]
[explosion]
[爆炸]
[both mumbling]
[两人都嘀咕着]
- You can buff that out.
- 你可以把它抛光掉。
- How could--
why would--
- 怎么可能--
为什么会——
I can't believe it!
我简直不敢相信！
[sighs]
[叹气]
I'll never see the
Warbling Water Lily bloom now.
我永远不会看到
鸣睡莲现在盛开。
[groaning]
[呻吟]
[groaning continues]
[呻吟继续]
both: Oh!
两人：哦！
Poor Squidward.
可怜的章鱼哥。
- Ooh, I have an idea.
- 哦，我有一个主意。
- Really?
What's that like?
- 真的吗？
那是什么样子的？
- Little monsters.
- 小怪物。
They ought to be locked up.
他们应该被关起来。
Throw away the key, then--
[shudders]
把钥匙扔掉，然后——
[颤抖]
[snoring]
[打鼾]
[muttering]
Lock up...
[嘀咕]
锁起来...
and throw them away.
并把它们扔掉。
[pleasant music]
[悦耳的音乐]
♪ ♪
[vocalizing]
[发声]
[sniffs]
[嗅嗅]
Ah! Ah!
啊!啊!
[both giggling]
[两人都咯咯笑]
[giggling continues]
[咯咯笑继续]
[screams]
[尖叫声]
Oh, oh, whew.
哦，哦，哇哦。
It was only a nightmare.
这只是一场噩梦。
[screams]
[尖叫声]
[both screaming]
[两人尖叫]
[all screaming]
[所有人尖叫]
- [muffled]
Good morning, Squidward.
- [低声]
早上好，章鱼哥。
- Would you get out
of my bedroom?
- 你能出去吗
我的卧室？
- Oh, we're not
in your bedroom, silly.
- 哦，我们不是
在你的卧室里，傻瓜。
- What?
How did I get here?
- 什么？
我是怎么到这里的？
- Patrick and I moved--
-帕特里克和我搬家了--
- Actually, I don't care.
- 事实上，我不在乎。
Humph.
哼。
Goodbye, Sponge--
再见，海绵——
[wailing]
[哀号]
[panting]
[气喘吁吁]
Spongebob, why is your house
海绵宝宝，为什么是你的房子
driving on the road?
开车在路上？
- Because we
turned it into a RV.
- 因为我们
把它变成了一辆房车。
- We didn't want you to
miss that flower blooming.
-我们不想让你这么做
怀念那朵盛开的花。
- Okay.
- 好的。
Hold on.
Who's driving?
坚持，稍等。
谁在开车？
- It's on auto-snail.
- 这是自动蜗牛。
- [meows]
- [喵]
- Come on,
let's get breakfast.
- 来吧，
我们去吃早餐吧。
- [soft giggling]
- [轻笑]
[chuckling]
[轻笑]
- [startles]
- [吃惊]
Hey, this looks pretty good.
嘿，这看起来很不错。
Huh?
啊？
[groaning]
[呻吟]
Ah.
啊。
[choking]
[窒息]
[inhales deeply]
[深吸一口气]
- You gonna eat that?
- 你要吃那个吗？
- Hey, Patrick,
let's give Gary a break.
- 嘿，帕特里克，
让我们让加里休息一下。
- Disengaging auto-snail!
- 解除自动蜗牛！
- [meowing]
- [喵喵叫]
- Hey, hop!
Ho!
- 嘿，跳！
嗬！
- [meowing]
[toy squeaking]
- [喵喵叫]
[玩具吱吱声]
- Let's see what
this pineapple can do!
- 让我们看看是什么
这个菠萝可以做！
Whee!
[laughs]
哎哟！
[笑]
Yeah!
是的！
On the road!
在路上！
- We got to get off this road!
- 我们必须离开这条路！
- No problem.
- 没问题。
[tires screeching]
[轮胎的尖叫声]
- Oh.
Hi, Squidward.
- 哦。
嗨，章鱼哥。
- [wailing]
- [哀号]
I'm not here!
This isn't happening!
我不在！
这不会发生！
[Johann Strauss's
"The Blue Danube"]
[约翰施特劳斯的
《蓝色多瑙河》]
♪ ♪
- [meowing]
[toy squeaking]
- [喵喵叫]
[玩具吱吱声]
- Whoo-hoo!
- 呼呼！
[glass smashes]
- [grunts]
[玻璃碎裂]
- [咕哝]
- Ah, we're here!
- 啊，我们到了！
- Huh? Huh?
[gasps]
- 啊？啊？
[喘气]
[pleasant music]
[悦耳的音乐]
The Warbling Water Lily!
睡莲的鸣叫！
[mutters]
[嘀咕]
Oh, it's so beautiful.
哦，太漂亮了。
And I have it all to my--
oh!
我拥有这一切——
哦！
[all exclaiming]
[camera shutters clicking]
[所有人惊呼]
[相机快门咔哒声]
Ow!
My back!
噢！
我的背！
Huh? Where is it?
啊？它在哪里？
- Is this that
Babbling Buttercup
- 这是那个吗
咿咿呀呀的毛茛
you were looking for?
你在找什么？
[curious chattering]
[好奇的喋喋不休]
- Aww, ohh.
- 哇哦。
[crinkling]
[起皱]
[all gasp]
[全都喘气]
[groans]
[呻吟]
[blows landing]
[吹着陆]
- Ooh.
- 哦。
- [grunts]
- [咕哝]
- [pained groaning]
- [痛苦的呻吟]
- [grunts]
- [咕哝]
[sniffs]
Mmm.
[嗅嗅]
嗯。
- [jibbers]
- [叽叽喳喳]
[sighs] Well,
[叹气]好吧，
that's one more vacation
down the drain.
这又是一个假期
付诸东流。
May as well go home.
也可以回家吧。
- Well, we got a long drive
ahead of us.
- 嗯，我们的车程很长
在我们前面。
We better go before we go
if you know what I mean-o.
我们最好在走之前先走
如果你明白我的意思-o。
- [chuckles]
- [轻笑]
Uh, not really.
呃，不是真的。
- Now, Squidward,
don't leave without us.
-现在，章鱼哥，
不要离开我们。
- Huh?
Of course not!
- 啊？
当然不是！
Only a monster
would leave you behind.
只是一个怪物
会把你抛在后面。
So I'm a monster.
所以我是一个怪物。
[whistling]
[吹口哨]
They'll be fine...
他们会没事的...
alone, on top of a mountain...
独自一人，在山顶上……
in the middle of nowhere.
在偏僻的地方。
Oh!
哦！
Oh, I can't do it!
哦，我做不到！
[boat beeping]
[船的嘟嘟声]
- Hey, you're really
- 嘿，你真是
getting the hang of
using toilet paper, Patrick.
掌握窍门
使用卫生纸，帕特里克。
- And next week,
I'm starting on two-ply.
- 下周，
我从两层开始。
- I'll get another roll
from the RV.
- 我再拿一卷
来自房车。
Hey, where is the RV?
嘿，房车在哪里？
- Well, maybe those guys
have seen it.
- 好吧，也许那些家伙
见过它。
Hey, hey!
Have you seen our pineapple?
嘿嘿！
你看到我们的菠萝了吗？
- [panting]
- [气喘吁吁]
- [screaming]
- [尖叫]
- Oh, no, I'm too late!
- 哦，不，我来晚了！
- [screaming]
- [尖叫]
- Hi-yah!
- 嗨呀！
Don't you dare
eat those morons!
你不敢吗
吃掉那些白痴！
[both giggling]
[两人都咯咯笑]
- Squidward,
they weren't eating us.
- 章鱼哥，
他们没有吃我们。
- We were just having
a tickle fight.
- 我们刚刚
一场挠痒痒的战斗。
- Sea-bears love it when
you tickle their bellies.
- 海熊喜欢它
你挠他们的肚子。
- But they hate it when
you karate chop their heinies.
- 但他们讨厌这样
你用空手道砍掉他们的荣耀。
[bear growls]
- Uh, tickle, tickle...
[熊咆哮]
- 呃，痒痒，痒痒……
[loud growling]
[大声咆哮]
- Squidward, they'll leave
you alone if you play dead!
- 章鱼哥，他们会离开
如果你装死，就只有你一个人了！
- Uh, here!
This'll help!
- 呃，在这里！
这会有帮助的！
Catch!
抓住！
- [mumbling]
- [咕哝]
[head squeaks]
[bear growling]
[头吱吱作响]
[熊咆哮]
- Bye!
Call me.
- 再见！
打电话给我。
You got my number.
你有我的号码。
Wow!
哇！
Was that a fun road trip
那是一次有趣的公路旅行吗
or was that a fun road trip?
或者那是一次有趣的公路旅行吗？
- Ha!
The funnerest!
- 哈！
最好玩的！
- More like the worst
road trip.
- 更像是最糟糕的
公路旅行。
My once chance to hear
the Warbling Water Lily
我一次有机会听到
鸣叫的睡莲
and you ruined it!
而你毁了它！
- Are you sure
about that, Squidward?
- 你确定吗
关于那件事，章鱼哥？
Oh, poor thing
just needed some love.
哦，可怜的东西
只是需要一些爱。
[kisses]
[亲吻]
- [gasps]
The Warbling Water Lily!
- [喘气]
睡莲的鸣叫！
[clarinet music]
[单簧管音乐]
So beautiful.
如此美丽。
♪ ♪
- Oh! My ears!
- 哦！我的耳朵！
My ears!
It hurts! It hurts!
我的耳朵！
好痛！好痛！
[boom]
[繁荣]
[screams]
[尖叫声]
- We're so happy for you,
Squidward!
- 我们为你感到高兴
章鱼哥！
- Engage auto-snail!
- 启用自动蜗牛！